(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-02T23:08:11.965374",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
※この配信は演出により激しく点滅する場面がございます
部屋を明るくし画面から十分離れてご視聴ください
[Notice] This broadcast contains scenes with flashing lights.
Please watch in a well-lit room and sit back from the screen.
君に逢いたい時だって
Even when I want to see you,
どこか　逢えない気持ちがある
I somehow feel like we can't meet.
だけど　本当の優しさが
But true kindness
そこにあるかも知れない
might just be found right there.
人込みに　揺られている
Swayed by the crowd,
どこかに宛てがあるわけじゃない
it's not like I have a destination.
独りきり　歩いても
Even if I walk all alone,
何か　解決することじゃない
it won't really solve anything.
自分が　本当に望んでる
The feeling that I
気持ちは　きっと
truly desire is surely...
これから　二人で
...for the two of us
歩いて行くことさ
to walk together from now on.
君に　逢いたい時だって
Even when I want to see you,
どこか　逢えない気持ちがある
I somehow feel like we can't meet.
だけど　本当の優しさが
But true kindness
そこに　あるかも知れない
might just be found right there.
二人　輝いた季節は
The season we shone together
きっと　これからも続いてく
will surely continue on.
だから　大切な未来に
So, into our precious future,
この想いを　残したい
I want to leave these feelings behind.
飽きるまで　話しても
Even if we talk until we're tired,
全部　分かり合えるわけじゃない
we can't understand everything.
言葉より　伝えたい
More than words, I want to convey
気持ちが　この胸にあふれてる
the feelings overflowing in my heart.
君がいつか　探した夢の
The continuation of the dream
続きは　きっと
you once searched for...
二人で　描いて行こう
...let's paint it together.
忘れないで
Please don't forget.
独りきり　孤独なようで保存
Though we seem lonely and alone,
皆　何かに悩んでいる
everyone is struggling with something.
すぐには　変わらないけれど
Even if things don't change right away,
とにかく　信じていたい保存
at least I want to believe.
流した　涙は捨てて
Leaving behind the tears we shed,
ずっと　君のそばで生きたい
I want to live by your side forever.
いつか　振り返った時に保存
So that when we look back someday,
後悔　したくないから
we won't have any regrets.
キミに
To you...
会いたいと言いたくて
I wanted to say that I want to see you...
二人
The season...
輝いた季節は
where we shone together...
後悔したくないから
Because I don't want to have any regrets.
叶わない 夢なんて
A dream that won't come true,
簡単に 口にはしたくない
I don't want to easily speak of it.
諦めた 瞬間に
The very moment you give up,
自分自身 終わらせてるだけ
you're only bringing an end to yourself.
もっと 単純に感じたい//もっと単純に感じたい
I want to feel things more simply.
キミのこと いつも//キミのこといつも
I always want to smile...
素直に 笑うよ//素直に笑うよ
...honestly at you.
未来は 続いていく//未来は続いていく
The future keeps going on.
キミが ホントにスキだって//キミがホントにスキだって
I want to keep...
いつも 心に飾ってたい//いつも心に飾ってたい
...the fact that I truly love you in my heart forever.
楽しさだけが 全てなら//楽しさだけが全てなら
If fun is all that matters,
本当の 愛じゃないから//本当の愛じゃないから
then it's not real love.
キミに
To you...
会いたいと言いたくて
I wanted to say that I want to see you.
二人 輝いた季節は
The season where we shone together...
きっと これからも続いていく
will surely continue from now on.
だから 大切な未来に
So, into our precious future...
この想いを 残したい
I want to leave these feelings.
キミに
To you...
会いたいと言いたくて
I wanted to say that I want to see you.
二人
Our...
輝いた季節は
...shining season...
みんなー！6周年ライブに来てくれてありぺこー！そして大変お待たせしました！
Everyone! Thank you so much for coming to my 6th anniversary live! And sorry to keep you waiting!
さ、さ、さ、騒が、けどね、みんなに楽しんでもらえるようなライブになってるぺこだから、是非ともお楽しみに！
It might be a little hectic, but it's a concert designed for everyone to enjoy, so please look forward to it!
そして！1曲目は「そこにあるかも知れない」を歌わせてもらったぺこ！
And for the first song, I performed \"Soko ni Aru Kamo Shirenai\" peko!
待っているということは今回のテーマは…そう！パチスロ第2弾！イェーイ！
Which means, the theme for this live is... Yes! Pachislot Part 2! Yay!
当たり演出もね、めちゃめちゃ色々ありますんで、是非とも次の曲は何来るかなって考えながら楽しんでもらえたら嬉しいぺこ！
There are lots of jackpot animations, so I'd be happy if you had fun guessing what song will come next, peko!
そして今回のハッシュタグはこちら！「#兎田ぺこら6周年記念LIVE」ぺこなんで、たくさんポストしてください！
And here's the hashtag for today: \"#UsadaPekoraRokusyuunenKinenLIVE\" peko, so please make lots of posts!
というわけで、そんじゃ早速回していくか！
Alright, let's spin the reels right away!
よいしょっと。あれ？お？
Here we go... Wait, what? Oh?
あ、始まった！
Oh, it started!
運命の一撃！
Stroke of Fate!
笑うべきだと分かった時は泣くべきじゃねえぺこ！
When you know you should be laughing, that's no time to cry, peko!
運命の一撃を 叩き込め！
Strike down... the blow of fate!
さん
に
いち
咲かすか
To make it bloom,
枯らすか 今
or to wither? Right now,
燃えるように
like it's burning,
陽が沈む
the sun is setting.
歯車が
The gears
回る
are turning.
ラッパが鳴れば
When the trumpet sounds,
チャカサマサマ
chaka-sama-sama,
まったなしの物語
a story with no time to lose.
ハッシャガラガラ
Hassha-gara-gara,
トッシャガラガラ
tossha-gara-gara,
真っ赤な過去が追いかける
the crimson past chases after us.
道化師の笑みに
Behind the jester's smile,
仮面の裏側
on the other side of the mask.
どう消したって消えない
No matter how you erase it, it won't disappear—
傷が痛んでも
even if the wound hurts.
咲かすか
To make it bloom,
枯らすか 今
or to wither? Right now,
燃えるように陽が沈む
the sun sets like it's burning.
真夜中の暗い孤独から
From the dark loneliness of midnight,
狂いだす
we start going mad.
微かに響く鐘が
The faintly echoing bell
陰る日々の道標
is a signpost for the fading days,
音の鳴る先へ
leading to where the sound goes.
ラッパが鳴れば
When the trumpet sounds,
ジャッカワラワラ
jakka-wara-wara,
真っ赤な死の演目の終止
the end of the crimson play of death.
真っ赤な幕の合間
Between the crimson curtains,
落下はまだか
is the fall not here yet?
真っ逆さま 突っ伏すように
Plunging headfirst, as if falling flat,
足をつかまれ
our feet are grabbed,
奈落の底まで
all the way down to the abyss.
明日さえも忘れて
Forgetting even tomorrow,
息もできない
we can't even breathe.
咲かすか
To make it bloom,
枯らすか 今
or to wither? Right now,
眠るように 目を閉じる
we close our eyes as if falling asleep.
身体中巡る猛毒から
From the deadly poison coursing through our bodies,
逃げ出す
we escape.
微かに響く鐘に
To the faintly echoing bell,
耳を澄ませ 生きるのか
listen closely... Will we live?
どちらか選べ さあ
Choose one of them, now!
解を待つ身のように
Like someone waiting for an answer,
未来だけ思えばいい
you only need to think of the future.
過去の足音消して さあ
Erase the footsteps of the past, now!
咲かすか
To make it bloom,
枯らすか 今
or to wither? Right now,
燃えるように陽が沈む
the sun sets like it's burning.
真夜中の深い孤独から
From the deep loneliness of midnight,
狂いだす
we start going mad.
運命が壊れるような
With a voice that sounds
声で叫べ 始まりの
as if destiny is breaking, shout!
合図 幕開け さあ舞って踊るさ
The signal, the curtain rises! Let's dance and spin!
誰しも最後には
In the end, everyone
涙 流す
sheds tears.
だから今は
So for now,
堪え進む
endure and move forward.
幕が下りるその時まで まだ
Until the curtain falls, still,
絶えず
without ceasing,
歯車が回る
the gears keep turning.
究極Vモンキー！
Ultimate V-Monkey!
ココロが止まらない
My heart won't stop!
何かをするのに
To do something,
理由なんかいらないね
you don't need any reasons.
熱くなるよ
It's heating up...
君を見ているだけで
Just by looking at you,
戦っているのよ
I am fighting.
期待はどんな時でも
No matter when, expectations...
もつれて迷い込む
...get tangled and go astray.
イチかバチか
All or nothing,
夢に向かい加速する
accelerating toward our dreams,
ココロが止まらない
my heart won't stop.
感じてる
I feel it.
悩み多き日常のターンに
In the turns of my trouble-filled daily life,
君といる時の自分が一番好きだよ
I love myself the most when I'm with you.
ココロは止まらない
My heart won't stop.
光の中
Within the light,
七色の水しぶきあげて
splashing rainbow-colored water spray,
新しい明日の風に向かい走り出そうよ
let's run toward the wind of a new tomorrow...
二人きりで
...just the two of us.
会いたい気持ちが
My desire to see you...
ため息に溶けていく
...melts into a sigh.
寂しい夜
On lonely nights,
そっとそばにいてくれた
you were quietly by my side.
泣き出しそうになった時
When I was on the verge of tears,
気づかないふりしてくれたね
you pretended not to notice.
重ねる唇から
From our overlapping lips,
こぼれる切なさも愛しさも
both sadness and tenderness overflow.
ココロが止まらない
My heart won't stop.
感じてる
I feel it.
もっとすべてを変えてみたい
I want to change everything even more.
願った奇跡がこんなにも近くにあったよ
The miracle I wished for was so close by.
ココロは止まらない
My heart won't stop.
通りすぎた
Passing through,
夏の匂い懐かしいね
the scent of summer is nostalgic.
君を好きになってから前より寂しがりやに
Since falling in love with you,
なってしまった
I've become much lonelier.
こわいものはたった一つ
There is only one thing I fear:
君が優しすぎること
that you are too kind.
たそがれが
Even if twilight...
風止めても
...stops the wind,
夢へのブレーキかからない
the brakes on my dreams won't engage.
ココロが止まらない
My heart won't stop.
感じてる
I feel it.
きっと答えは一つじゃない
I'm sure there isn't just one answer.
君に逢うためだけにとても優しくなれるよ
Just to see you, I can become so gentle.
ココロは止まらない
My heart won't stop.
月のしずく
Like moon drops,
ずっと君を探してた
I've been searching for you all along.
同じ時同じ星見上げてこのままきっと
Looking up at the same star at the same time,
色あせぬように
surely like this, so it won't fade.
リーチ！
Reach!
輝くマリンブルー
Shining marine blue,
やっと出会えたサマータイム
the summer time we finally met.
ミラクルマリンパワー
Miracle marine power!
「せーの」で飛び込もう！
On three, let's dive in!
Go! Go! Let's Go! SEA STORY
太陽燦々 裸足で 駆け出して行こう ビーチへ
The sun is shining! Let's run barefoot to the beach!
ココナッツ バケーション 見つけに行こう 海のワンダーランド
Let's find a coconut vacation in the ocean wonderland!
みんな歌えば
If everyone sings...
イルカたちとジャンプ
...jump with the dolphins!
カニとタコのダンス
The crab and octopus are dancing!
スペシャルな夢を描こう
Let's paint a special dream!
輝く マリンブルー
Shining marine blue!
やっと出会えた サマータイム
Finally we met, summertime!
ミラクル マリンパワー
Miracle marine power!
せーので飛び込もう
Let's dive in on three!
Go! Go! Let's Go! SEA STORY
海底探検泳いで 一緒に遊びに行こうよ
Swimming on an undersea exploration, let's play together!
笑顔が何よりの たった一つの宝物だよ
Your smile is, more than anything, our single treasure!
シャチの背中に
On the back of an orca...
サンゴのトンネル
...passing through a coral tunnel...
クラゲのリズム
...with the rhythm of the jellyfish!
始まる 夢のステージ
The dream stage is starting!
きらめく マリンスノー
Sparkling marine snow!
みんな一緒に エブリデイ
Everyone together, everyday!
スペシャル サマーソング
Special summer song!
せーので始めよう
Let's begin on three!
Go! Go! Let's Go! SEA STORY
輝く マリンブルー
Shining marine blue!
やっと出会えた サマータイム
Finally we met, summertime!
ミラクル マリンパワー
Miracle marine power!
せーので飛び込もう
Let's dive in on three!
グレート マリンブルー
Great marine blue!
水平線の彼方まで
All the way to the horizon!
ミラクル マリンパワー
Miracle marine power!
せーので飛び込もう
Let's dive in on three!
Go! Go! Let's Go! SEA STORY
ルパン三世のテーマ
[Theme of Lupin III]
BIG CHANCE
真赤な薔薇は あいつの唇
A crimson rose is her lips,
やさしく抱きしめて くれとねだる
begging to be embraced gently.
瞳の奥に 獲物を映して
Reflecting the prey deep in his eyes,
寂しく問いかける 愛の在りか
he lonely asks, "Where is love?"
男には 自分の世界がある たとえるなら
A man has his own world, if you were to compare it...
空をかける ひとすじの流れ星
...to a single shooting star streaking across the sky.
孤独な笑みを 夕陽にさらして
Exposing a lonely smile to the setting sun...
背中で泣いてる
Crying behind his back,
男の美学
is a man's aesthetic.
真珠の色は
The color of pearls
あいつのまなざし
is the look in his eyes,
遥かな幸せを
visualizing a distant happiness
夢に描く
in a dream.
いためることを
Being too afraid
恐れるあまりに
of causing pain,
冷たく突き放す
there are times when pushing away coldly
愛もあるさ
is also a form of love.
男には 自分の世界がある
A man has his own world.
たとえるなら
If you were to compare it...
風をはらい 荒れ狂う稲光
...to sweeping away the wind like raging lightning.
都会の闇に
Melting his body
体を溶かして
into the darkness of the city,
口笛吹いてる
whistling along,
男の美学
is a man's aesthetic.
アメエエエエズィンンググレエエエエス！
Ameeeezing Greeeeace!
ハアアアアアスィィィツアアアアサアアアン！
Hoooow sweeeet the souuuund!
ザッセエエエイザラアアアアライコミイイイイ！
Thaeeet saaaaved a wreuuuutch like meeee!
乙女アタック突入！
Otome Attack, initiate!
勝負ペコ！
Let's battle, peko!
楽勝ペコ！
Easy win, peko!
夜を彷徨う影が
The shadows wandering the night
光を裂こうと吠える
howl to tear apart the light.
罪深き羊たち
O sinful sheep,
平伏しなさい 容赦はしません
prostrate yourselves, I will show no mercy.
守るべき人のため
For the sake of those I must protect,
正義のため
for the sake of justice,
優しい心
with a kind heart
優しい愛
and gentle love,
のために
for their sake.
どんなに傷つこうと 祈りましょう
Let us pray, no matter how much we get hurt.
御意に！
As you wish!
誓う命かけて
Pledging my life,
援護を！戦場、翔けて
support me! Soaring through the battlefield,
信じた仲間たちと
together with the comrades I trusted,
この手に宿る力 信じて
believing in the power dwelling in these hands.
狂い咲けよ 咲き誇れ 闘志の華よ
Bloom wildly, in full glory, flower of fighting spirit!
戦の地に降り立つ夢
A dream descending onto the battlefield
大輪の炎 闇を蹴散らして
Scatter the darkness with giant flames
勝利を 勇気と熱を 糧に 掴め
Seize victory, fueled by courage and heat
連れて行こう 辿り着く金色の空
Let me take you to the golden sky we will reach
笑顔を育む大地へ
Toward the earth that nurtures smiles
夜はいずれ去り 朝が訪れる
The night will eventually fade, and morning will come
全てを越えて 君の愛 叶う
Transcending everything, your love will come true
星の巡りを辿り 手にした希望の十字
Tracing the orbit of stars, I held the cross of hope in my hand
後悔などしないわ 救いは私が与える
I will have no regrets; salvation is what I shall grant
発条仕掛けの処 踊れ影よ
O clockwork demon, dance, shadow!
光が導き舞い 遊戯はおしまい
Guided by light as we dance, the game is over
大胆不敵な技 目指す場所は
With a daring technique, our destination is...
勝利の席 開く艶 命生まれる楽園
The seat of victory, blooming allure, a paradise where life is born
さぁ 共に行きましょう
Now, let's go together
正義は必ず勝つ いつでも
Justice will always prevail, forevermore
空を渡る 溢れだし燃える想いが
Crossing the sky, overflowing and burning feelings...
鮮やかに彩る虹へ
...turn into a vibrantly colored rainbow
瞳を交わして 絆を 伸ばす手と手 結べば
If we lock eyes and connect our reaching hands with our bond...
見えてくる新しい朝が
...we can see a new morning coming into view
時を越えて 暁の幸せはほら
Across time, look, the happiness of dawn...
誰の上にも降り注ぐ
...shines down upon everyone
胸の中を 雨はやがて止み 渇き癒すよ
Within my heart, the rain will eventually stop, healing the thirst
過去を解き放て 君の夢を問う
Release the past, and follow your dreams
貴方と想いを 数えきれないほどの出会いと別れ 重ねて
Sharing feelings with you, through countless meetings and departures...
真実 人は生きる意味を見つける
...in truth, people find the meaning of life
狂い咲けよ 咲き誇れ 闘志の華よ
Bloom wildly, in full glory, flower of fighting spirit!
戦の地に降り立つ夢
A dream descending onto the battlefield
大輪の炎 闇を蹴散らして
Scatter the darkness with giant flames
勝利を 勇気と熱を 糧に 掴め
Seize victory, fueled by courage and heat
連れて行こう 辿り着く金色の空
Let me take you to the golden sky we will reach
笑顔を育む大地へ
Toward the earth that nurtures smiles
祝福が 夜はいずれ去り 朝が訪れる
Blessings... the night will eventually fade, and morning will come
全てを越えて 君の愛 叶う
Transcending everything, your love will come true
待っていたぞ ペコラ
I've been waiting for you, Pekora!
連れて行こう！
Let's take them down!
バトルボーナス ゲット！
Battle Bonus, GET!
ヘイ！ヘイ！ヘイ！ヘイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
Welcome to this crazy Time
このイカれた時代へようこそ 君は
Welcome to this crazy era, you are a...
tough boy tough boy tough boy tough boy tough boy
まともな奴ほど feel so bad
The more decent someone is, the more they feel so bad
正気でいられるなんて運がイイぜ you,
You're lucky to even stay sane, you...
tough boy tough boy tough boy tough boy tough boy
時はまさに世紀末
The time is truly the end of the century
澱んだ街角で僕らは出会った
On a stagnant street corner, we met each other
Keep you burning 駆け抜けて
Keep you burning, run through...
この腐敗と自由と暴力のまっただなか
...in the very midst of this corruption, freedom, and violence!
No boy no cry 悲しみは
No boy, no cry, sadness...
絶望じゃなくて明日のマニフェスト
...is not despair, but a manifesto for tomorrow
We are living, living in the eighties
We still fight, fighting in the eighties
どこもかしこも傷だらけ
Everywhere is covered in wounds
うずくまって泣いてては はじまらないから
Crouching down and crying won't get us anywhere
tough boy tough boy tough boy tough boy
どっちを向いても feel so sad
No matter which way I look, I feel so sad
だけど死には至らない 気分はどうだい？
But it's not fatal, how are you feeling?
tough boy tough boy tough boy tough boy
ここは永遠のロックランド
This is the eternal Rockland
拳を握りしめ僕らは出会った
Clenching our fists, we met each other
Keep you burning 駆け抜けて
Keep you burning, run through
この狂気と希望と幻滅のまっただなか
Right in the midst of this madness, hope, and disillusionment
No boy no cry 進まなきゃ
No boy no cry, we must move forward
勢いを増した向かい風の中を
Through the headwind that has gained momentum
We are living, living in the eighties
We still fight, fighting in the eighties
野うさぎ討伐戦 突入！
Nousagi Subjugation Battle, commence!
お前の英雄は超強欲に勝ってみせるぺこ！
Your hero will show you they can defeat Super Greed, peko!
PUSHぺこ！
Push, peko!
ごちそうさまです！
Thank you for the feast!
完全撃破
[Completely Defeated]
This is a fate that brought us here watch my long shot
Feel like I am falling into the flame of lies
Tell me what do you want from me
Trying not to step back to where I used to belong
Looking for the escape from pain
I will cross my fingers hoping not to be sacrificed
約束したんだ君とその希望に
I made a promise to you and that hope
Get in the raid Get ready for the time to come
浮かび上がるシルエット 追いかけ
Chasing after the rising silhouette
Drop down the reason why I'm standing here alone
Maybe it's already too late to regain
運命としてかかげた灯を
The light we held up as our destiny,
失くさないで
don't let it fade away.
Ever again
What if I could right my wrongs and save you from the pain
It's not enough It's not enough for me
to break the rule upon this world
I will never gonna leave you
I will never leave you,
never wanna lose you
never want to lose you
we'll make it in the end
Not backing down for real
I won't trace someone else's life
I know who I am
Blame me if I messed up anything
take the risk of everything
justify this cruel world
闇の真似して 叫び声上げて
Imitating the darkness, crying out,
狂おしくって 吸い込まれてく 影を残して
madly being sucked in, leaving behind a shadow.
I will cross my fingers hoping not to be sacrificed
息を殺して 潜み通すのさ Keep on warning
Holding my breath, I'll sneak my way through, keep on warning
Get in the way, get ready for the time to come
再び死に至るを追いかけ
Chasing after death once again...
Make up! Make out! Break out! ... It's all up to you!
何度だっていいんだ 覚悟してんだ
I don't care how many times it takes, I'm prepared!
全て守ると決めたよ 君がいるから
I've decided to protect everything because you are here!
絡み合う未来を この手で変えてみせると信じて
Believing I'll change the tangled future with these hands,
すべきことは分かっているから
because I know what I must do.
Take this pain away from me
この胸の鼓動にのせて
riding on this heartbeat.
There's no way I can fail
見届けておくれよ 願いを
watch over my wish!
強欲だ
Greedy
超強欲 BONUS
Super Greedy BONUS
Shut down the reason why I'm standing here all alone
Maybe it's already too late to regain
温もり閉じて 掲げた灯を 無くさないで
Close up the warmth, but don't lose the light you held high.
Please yourself, don't forget, this is your fate
What if I could write my wrongs and save you from the fate
It's not enough, it's not enough for me to break...
...the rule upon this world
I will never gonna leave you,
never wanna lose you, make it in the end
Not backing down for real,
I won't trade someone else's life
I know who I am
待っていたのはこの瞬間！
What I've been waiting for is this very moment!
ボーナス確定ぺこ！
Bonus confirmed, peko!
錬金術師であるのが功を奏したか！
Did being an alchemist pay off...!
一撃でししし...
In a single hit, shi-shi-shi...
みんなの想いを背負い
Carrying everyone's wishes...
聞こえますか…？ 風に広がるメロディ
Can you hear it...? The melody spreading in the wind
天に 解き放て
Release it to the heavens!
聞こえますか…？ 命に始まる脈動
Can you hear it...? The pulsation starting from life
愛を 突き上げて
Thrusting up our love!
遥か彼方 閉じた音楽 届いたあの日
That day when the locked-away music reached from far away,
風は泣いて 笑いやがて 伝え紡ぐ鼓動を歌にした
the wind cried, then smiled, eventually turning the spun pulse into a song.
そして
And then...
夢は 開くよ 見たことない世界の果て
dreams will open up at the edge of an unseen world.
Yes, just believe
神様も知らない ヒカリで歴史を創ろう
Let's create history with a light unknown even to God,
不死なる炎(メロディ) 未来照らす
an immortal melody will light up the future.
一緒に飛ばないか？
Won't you fly with me?
just feeling 涙で濡れたハネ
Just feeling... wings wet with tears...
重くて羽撃けない日は wish
on days they're too heavy to flap, wish.
その右手に添えよう
Let's place onto that right hand
描くチカラを
the power to draw.
鳥のように はためき合うよ singing heart
Fluttering like birds, our singing hearts.
いつの日にか解る時が来るから
Because the day will come when you understand,
ずっと 忘れない
I will never forget.
その時には 心のあるがままに
At that time, just as your heart dictates,
笑顔 忘れない
don't forget to smile.
言葉なんていらない
We don't need any words...
まだ見ぬ地平の先
beyond the unseen horizon.
強く 強く 手と手 繋ぎ
Tightly, tightly, holding hands,
逆光に舞う 七色の翼
seven-colored wings dance in the backlight.
そして 生きる 今を
And so, living in the present,
見た事ない 明日の先へ yes, just believe
toward the unseen tomorrow, yes, just believe!
1000年後の今日も 生まれ変わって 歌いたい
Even today, a thousand years from now, reborn, I want to sing.
暖かいよ この温もり
It's so warm, this warmth...
絶対 離さない
I'll never let it go.
just feeling 運命なんてない
Just feeling, there is no such thing as fate.
物語は自分にある jump
The story lies within yourself, jump!
逃げ出したくなったら
If you ever want to run away,
宇宙を見上げよう
let's look up at the universe.
勇気こそが 輝くんだよ singing star
It is courage that shines, singing star!
遥か 彼方 星が 音楽となった…彼の日
Far, far away, that day when stars turned into music...
たぶん 共に 出会い 響き
Probably meeting and resonating together,
神話の一つに紡いだ
we wove it into one of the myths.
何も 怖くないよ
There is nothing to fear.
見た事ない 世界の果てへ
To the edge of an unseen world,
yes, just believe
神様も知らない ヒカリで歴史を創ろう
Let's create history with a light unknown even to God.
不死なる太陽 未来照らす
The immortal sun illuminates the future.
一緒に飛ばないか？
Won't you fly with me?
just feeling 涙で濡れたハネ
Just feeling... wings wet with tears...
重くて羽撃けない日は wish
on days they're too heavy to flap, wish.
旋律は溶け合って
Melodies melt together...
シンフォニーへと
into a symphony,
鳥のように はためき合うよ singing heart
fluttering like birds, our singing hearts.
虹は架かる すべては夢と共に
A rainbow will arch, everything together with dreams.
野うさぎ剣を押し込め！
Push down the Nousagi Sword!
行け！ 疾風のごとく
Go! Like a gale,
宿命の剣士よ
O fated warrior,
闇にまぎれて
disappear into the darkness.
何故 戦うのか
Why do you fight?
...のか
...why do we fight?
それは剣に訊け
Ask your sword.
正義だとか愛など 俺は追いかけない
I don't chase after things like justice or love.
闇に生まれ 闇に忍び 闇を切り裂く
Born in darkness, hiding in darkness, tearing through darkness...
遥かな 古代から受け継いだ 使命だから
For it is a mission inherited from ancient times.
行け！ 疾風のごとく 魔戒の騎士よ
Go! Like a gale, Makai Knight!
月満つる夜に 金色になれ
Become golden on the night of the full moon!
雄々しき姿の 孤独な戦士よ
A lonely warrior of heroic figure!
魂を込めた 怒りの刃叩きつけて
Strike with the blade of wrath filled with your soul,
時代に輝け 牙狼！
shine in this era, GARO!
いつの日か おまえには わかって欲しい
Someday, I want you to understand...
戦いだけに生きた 俺の胸の内を
what lies within the heart of one who lived only to fight.
愛にはぐれ 愛を憎み 愛を求める
Straying from love, hating love, seeking love...
わずかな安らぎさえ うち捨てた誓いだけど
even throwing away the slightest peace of mind, though it is a vow.
立て！ 修羅のごとく 魔戒の騎士よ
Stand! Like an Asura, Makai Knight!
運命の歌の 命ずるままに
At the command of the song of fate!
月夜に輝く 孤高の戦士よ
A solitary warrior shining in the moonlit night!
迫り来る影を 一網打尽叩き斬って
Mow down the approaching shadows, striking them all down,
気高く吠えろ 牙狼！
howl nobly, GARO!
行け！ 疾風のごとく 魔戒の騎士よ
Go! Like a gale, Makai Knight!
月満つる夜に 金色になれ
Become golden on the night of the full moon!
雄々しき姿の 孤独な戦士よ
A lonely warrior of heroic figure!
魂を込めた 怒りの刃叩きつけて
Strike with the blade of wrath filled with your soul,
時代に輝け 牙狼！
shine in this era, GARO!
行け 疾風のごとく 定めの騎士よ
Go like a gale, destined knight!
闇に光を
Light into the darkness...
今度こそ、君だけは幸せにしてみせるぺこ！
This time, I'll definitely make you happy, peko!
ボーナス確定！
Bonus confirmed!
これが実力ぺこ！
This is my true power, peko!
心よ原始に戻れ ～2012 Version～
[Song: Return to Origin of Your Heart ~2012 Version~]
悲しい響きが化石に変わるよ もうすぐ
Those sad sounds will soon turn into fossils.
あなたのその痛みを眠りの森へと ひそやかに導いてあげる
Your pain will be secretly led to the forest of sleep.
おやすみ すべてに一途すぎた迷い子たち
Good night to all the overly earnest stray children,
はがゆさが胸に進化する日まで
until the day your impatience evolves in your chest.
生命はまぶしい朝を待っている
Life is waiting for the dazzling morning.
最後の懺悔もかなわぬなら
Even if your final confession isn't granted,
いつか時代の夜が明ける
someday the dawn of a new era will break.
世界よ まぶたを閉じて
O world, close your eyes.
生命は目覚めて時を紡ぎだす
Life is awakening, spinning time.
あなたの証拠をさかのぼるように
As if retracing the evidence of your existence.
そして光が胸に届く
And then the light will reach your heart.
心よ原始に戻れ
O heart, return to the beginning.
涙の岸辺でずっとたたずんだ気持ちを
Those feelings that lingered forever on the shore of tears,
優しく包むように秘密の薬が思い出の沖へと運ぶよ
gently, like a secret medicine, carrying them to the open sea of memories.
おやすみ モラルに汚れていた指も耳も
Good night to your fingers and ears, once soiled by morality.
この腕の中でもう眠りなさい
Go to sleep now inside these arms of mine.
生命はまぶしい朝を待っている
Life is waiting for the dazzling morning.
破れた聖書を抱きしめるより
Rather than clutching a torn bible,
いつか時代の夜が明ける
someday the dawn of a new era will break.
あなたよ 祈りを捨てて
O you, cast aside your prayers.
生命は目覚めて時を紡ぎだす
Life is awakening, spinning time.
自然の法則にその身をまかせ
Entrust your body to the laws of nature.
そして光が胸に届く
And then the light will reach your heart.
心よ原始に戻れ
O heart, return to the beginning.
生命はまぶしい朝を待っている
Life is waiting for the dazzling morning.
最後の懺悔もかなわぬなら
Even if your final confession isn't granted,
いつか時代の夜が明ける
someday the dawn of a new era will break.
世界よ まぶたを閉じて
O world, close your eyes.
生命は目覚めて時を紡ぎだす
Life is awakening, spinning time.
あなたの証拠をさかのぼるように
As if retracing the evidence of your existence.
残留光が胸に届く
And then the light will reach your heart.
心よ原始に戻れ
O heart, return to the beginning.
ノエル？ フレア？ マリン？
Noel? Flare? Marine?
みんな、どこ行っちゃったぺこなの？
Where did everyone go, peko?
まあいっか、３期生ならなんとかなるよねきっと
Oh well, since we are the third gen, we'll surely figure something out!
ということで！
And with that!
ここまではたくさんのゲストのみんなとたくさんの曲を歌ってきましたが、みんな、いかが...
We have sung many songs with a lot of guests up until now, how did everyone...
どうですか？温まりましたか？
How was it? Did you warm up?
楽しんでくれていますか？
Are you all having fun?
最後にもね 一曲ぺこら また歌いますので
Pekora will sing one last song at the end,
そちらもお楽しみに ということで
so look forward to that! And with that...
ここからはグッズ紹介！
...it's time for the merch introduction!
お？あれ？
Oh? Wait, what?
おっ 光った！
Oh, it lit up!
お？ということは？
Oh? Which means...?
キタキタキタキター！
Here it comes, here it comes!
ということで 兎田ぺこら活動6周年記念グッズを紹介するぺこー！
So, I'll be introducing Usada Pekora's 6th Anniversary merch, peko!
まずは一つ目は こちらから！トゥルン！
First up is this one! Ta-da!
ぺこら推し法被！
The Pekora Fan Happi!
こちらは憂姫はぐれ先生に描いていただきました！
This was illustrated by Yuuki Hagure-sensei!
もうね 着るだけで推しをアピールできる
Just wearing it lets you show off your favorite oshi!
イベントでも着てきてほしいぺこです！
I hope you wear it to events, peko!
めちゃめちゃ可愛い法被ぺこなんで ぜひともよろー！
It's an incredibly cute happi, so please check it out!
仕様変更：そして二つ目は こちら！トゥルン！
And the second one is this! Ta-da!
な な な なんと！ついに！
W-W-W-What?! Finally...
ぺこらマミーも写っているグッズが出てしまいました！
...merch featuring Pekora Mammy has been released!
こちら ラバーマットです！
This is the Rubber Mat!
イラストはHikoさんにお願いしております！
The illustration was done by Hiko-san!
テーマはカジノの兎田ぺこらとぺこらマミーです！
The theme is Usada Pekora and Pekora Mammy in a casino!
ついに出てしまった マミーが。
Mammy has finally made her debut!
だからね ぜひともぺこらマミー大好きな人も
So, everyone who loves Pekora Mammy...
お手に取ってもらえると嬉しいぺこです！
...I'd be so happy if you got one, peko!
そして ラバーマットがあるということは 三つ目は？
And since we have a rubber mat, the third one is...
こちら！
...this!
はい カードスリーブもちゃんとあるぺこです！
Yes, we also have card sleeves, peko!
60枚入りでね
It comes in a pack of 60,
イラストは先ほどと同じHikoさんにお願いしております！
and the illustration is also by Hiko-san!
なんとこちら ホロカでも使えますので
Remarkably, you can use these in Holoca!
是非ともホロカで遊んでいる方は使っていただけると嬉しいぺこです！
So if you play Holoca, I'd love for you to use them, peko!
そして 四つ目は こちら！
And fourthly, this one!
可愛いね ぺこーにゃぬいぐるみキーホルダー！
The cute Pekornya plushie key chain!
カバンにつけてもよし
You can attach it to your bag,
旅行先に持って行くのもよしの
or take it with you when you travel—
持ち運びやすいサイズのぬいぐるみとなっております ぺこ！
it's a plushie that's super easy to carry around, peko!
こちらなんと フルセット購入の特典がございます！
And there's actually a bonus for purchasing the full set!
数量限定ver.で 直筆サイン入りポストカードがあります！
The limited edition ver. comes with a hand-signed postcard!
そして通常ver.は 箔押し複製サイン入りのポストカードとなっておりまして
And the standard ver. comes with a foil-stamped duplicate signature postcard,
はぐれ先生の法被のイラストとなっております！
featuring Hagure-sensei's happi illustration!
ぜひとも じゃんじゃんバリバリ買ってぺこー！
Please go ahead and buy them, peko!
それでは 最後は何の曲かな？
Well then, what will the final song be?
お楽しみに！
Look forward to it!
係員をお呼びください
Please call the staff.
ちょっと！ぺこ、ライブできない、ライブできない！
Hey! Peko can't do the live show!
係員をお呼びください
Please call the staff.
直してちょうだい！
Fix this, please!
おい 監視カメラ見えてんだろ？おい どうにか
Hey, you can see me through the security camera, right? Do something!
係員をお呼びください
Please call the staff.
どうにか！直して早く！
Do something! Fix it quickly!
ライブできないぺこだよ！
I can't do my live show, peko!
係員をお呼びください
Please call the staff.
叩いて 叩いてもダメぺこでしょ！
Hitting it... Hitting it won't work, peko!
叩いて 蹴っても直らないだろ！ちょっと！しっかり！
Hitting and kicking it won't fix it! Hey! Get it together!
係員をお呼びください
Please call the staff.
仮想の世に生まれ 生きること
To be born and live in a virtual world,
即ち 戦い、勝つこと
in other words, means to fight and win.
時代と戦い 己が宿命と戦い
Fighting the era, fighting one's own destiny,
自己自身に打ち勝つ
and conquering oneself.
いつの世も大差はなし
In any era, there is no great difference.
人の生き様が 一瞬の煌めきが 歴史をつむいでいく
A person's way of life, a momentary spark, continues to weave history.
今こそ胸に刻め 我が生き様を！
Now is the time to engrave it in your heart—my way of life!
永久に語り継げ
Tell the tale for eternity,
兎田の魂を！
of Usada's soul!
戦の炎 灯してみせよう！
The flames of battle, I shall show you I can light them!
Are you ready?
Shall We Dance? 始めよう
Shall We Dance? Let's begin.
勝利の祝杯あげる前に
Before raising the victory toast,
Relax Your Body 深呼吸
Relax Your Body, take a deep breath.
そうすりゃだんだん高まる
That way, it'll gradually build up.
Passion Force
Passion Force!
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6
膝もっと引き上げて右手を上げ YEAH!
Raise your knees higher and lift your right hand, YEAH!
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6
○○○○○○ 六文銭
Circle, circle, circle, circle, circle, circle, Rokumonsen!
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6
まだまだいけるはず！もっともっともっともっともっともっと！
You can still do more! More, more, more, more!
Take a Chance! Take a Chance!
勝利のために
For the sake of victory!
Take a Chance! Take a Chance! Take a Chance!
Well Done!
SANADA DA DANCE SANADA DA DANCE
ひのもといちのつわもの
The greatest warrior in Japan!
CHA RA CHA CHA CHA CHA RA CHA CHA CHA
不惜身命だぜ
With no regard for our own lives!
SANADA DA DANCE SANADA DA DANCE
急げ夜が明ける前に
Hurry, before dawn breaks!
CHA RA CHA CHA CHA CHA RA CHA CHA CHANCE
赤く赤く備えたなら
If you are prepared in red,
踊れ！歌え！SANADANCE 歌CISE
Dance! Sing! SANADANCE Exercise!
Wow Wow Wow...
(It's Cypher time)
Close your eyes 瞑想
Close your eyes, meditation
Don't think... Feel
感覚研ぎ澄ませたなら高まる
Once your senses are sharpened, it rises—
Passion Force
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6
フロントキックでツイストかまして 視線は下げずに、はい、ポーズ☆
Do a twist with a front kick, keep your eyes up, and strike a pose!
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6
回って回ってプンプン回って回転スピード増し増し
Spin, spin, spin around, increase the rotation speed!
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6
勢いつけて！そうだ！もっともっともっともっともっともっと！
Get momentum! That's right! More, more, more, more!
Change the world! Change the world!
Do or Do not
Change the world! Change the world! Change the world!
There is no try
SANADA DA DANCE SANADA DA DANCE
ハート燃やして不夜城
Burn your heart, sleepless castle!
CHA RA CHA CHA CHA CHA RA CHA CHA CHA
但惜身命だぜ
But I value my own life!
SANADA DA DANCE SANADA DA DANCE
心躍らせるために
To make your heart dance!
CHA RA CHA CHA CHANCE
CHA RA CHA CHA CHA, CHA RA CHA CHA CHANCE
熱く熱く構えたなら
If you stand hot and ready,
走れ！回せ！しゃがめ！伸ばせ！
Run! Spin! Crouch! Stretch!
空に叫べ！SANADANCE 歌CISE
Shout to the sky! SANADANCE Exercise!
Wow Wow Wow...
苦しい時や 辛い時には 体動かせよ SANADANCE
When times are tough or painful, move your body! SANADANCE
天上天下 唯我独尊
Above heaven and below earth, I alone am honored.
みんなで踊ろうぜ SANADANCE
Let's all dance together, SANADANCE!
Let's Go!
Take a Chance! Change the world!
深呼吸 Ba Hoo-ooo!
Take a deep breath... Ba Hoo-ooo!
本日も最終最後の時間まで、兎田ぺこら6周年ライブにお付き合いいただきまして誠にありがとうございました。
Thank you very much for staying with us until the very end of the Usada Pekora 6th Anniversary Live today.
はい、ありがとうございました。ありがとうございました。
Yes, thank you very much! Thank you!
残念ではございますが、まもなく本日のライブはすべて終了とさせていただきます。
Regrettably, today's live performance will be ending shortly.
メンバーシップカードをお持ちのお客様にご案内申し上げます。
We have an announcement for customers who hold a membership card.
メンバーシップカードをお持ちの方は、この後の10時15分より行われるアンコールライブにもご参加いただけます。
Those with membership cards can participate in the encore live starting at 10:15 PM.
お持ちでない方もまだ間に合いますので、これを機にぜひご加入ください。
Even if you don't have one, there is still time, so please take this opportunity to join!
また、グッズ販売の方もまもなくカートオープンとなります。
Also, the merchandise sales cart will be opening shortly.
10時10分より販売となりますので、ご購入をご検討の皆様は販売サイトにてご購入ください。
Sales will begin at 10:10 PM, so please visit the store page if you wish to purchase.
明日のご案内を申し上げます。
Here is the schedule for tomorrow.
明日の営業は通常通り夜から配信を行います。
We will stream in the evening as usual.
明日も兎田ぺこら、張り切って参りますので、ご来店お待ちしております。
Usada Pekora will be in high spirits tomorrow as well, so we look forward to your visit.
大変なご名残惜しくはございますが、本日はこれにてライブ終了とさせていただきます。
Although it is deeply regrettable to say goodbye, this concludes today's live performance.
最終最後までお付き合いいただき、ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much for staying with us until the very end.